Marvin C. Griffin papers, Inclusive: 1940-2011, undated, Bulk: 1960-1999, undated
Baylor University, The Texas Collection
Marvin C. Griffin papers
Inclusive: 1940-2011, undated, Bulk: 1960-1999, undated
Baylor University, The Texas Collection http://www.baylor.edu/lib/texas/
3837
Griffin, Marvin Collins, 1923 - 2013
74 document boxes and 30 oversized boxes.
The Marvin C. Griffin papers include both written and recorded materials pertaining to Reverend Marvin Griffin's ministerial research and sermons, his political involvement, and his leadership in the Baptist Convention on the state and national level.
Administrative Information
Physical Description
General condition: Good.
Biography/Profile
Marvin Collins Griffin was born in Wichita, Kansas, on February 20, 1923. He was the son of William Marvin Collins and Beulah Howell. Raised by his uncle and aunt near Dallas, Texas, Griffin felt a call to the ministry at the age of seven.
Griffin used his education to prepare for a career in preaching the gospel and fighting for African American civil rights. He spent his youth in the Dallas public school system. In 1943, Griffin graduated with a Bachelor of Arts degree from Bishop College. Four years later, he earned a degree in Divinity from Oberlin Graduate School of Theology. In 1955, Griffin became the first African American to graduate from Southwestern Baptist Theological Seminary when he earned a Master of Religious Education degree. In 1990, Griffin received his Doctorate of Ministry from Austin Presbyterian Theological Seminary.
Reverend Griffin began preaching in 1940 and was ordained two years later. While earning his degree from Oberlin, Griffin served as a professor at the Oklahoma Baptist School of Religion (1944-1948). His first significant pastoral assignment was New Hope Baptist Church in Waco. From 1951 to 1969, Griffin led his growing congregation in social activism within the community. He began an extensive radio broadcast ministry and led various marches and pickets in Waco.
In 1969, Griffin relocated to Ebenezer Baptist Church in Austin, Texas, where he remained for the next forty-two years. Once again, Griffin believed that his church should be involved in the spiritual and secular life of the community. He led the church’s efforts in creating the East Austin Economic Development Corporation (EAEDC) in 1998. This organization allowed the church to assist the underprivileged through housing programs, day care centers, counseling, and financial assistance. In 2002, the EAEDC building was renamed in honor of Marvin Griffin. Reverend Griffin retired from his pastorship of the Ebenezer Baptist Church on July 31, 2011.
In addition to his pastoral duties, Griffin was also involved in local politics and denominational affairs. He served as the first African American president of the Austin Independent School District Board of Directors when the schools were using buses to encourage desegregation. Griffin was also involved in the Missionary Baptist General Convention of Texas, he was the Director of the Christian Education Enrichment Program at the National Baptist Fellowship of Churches, and he served as a Director-Lecturer for the Teacher Training Department of the National Baptist Sunday School Congress.
Griffin married Lois King on August 5, 1944. They had three daughters: Marva Lois Carter, Gaynelle Jones, and Ria Griffin. Mrs. Lois Griffin passed away in 2006 and Marvin Griffin passed away on December 25, 2013.
Scope and Content
TheMarvin C. Griffin papers begin with Griffin's education in 1940 and end with his retirement in 2011. The Ministry series is the first and by far the largest series in the collection. It is divided into two subseries. The Personal subseries includes ministerial research for specific organizations as well as extensive research for radio broadcasts and sermons. The National Baptists subseries includes collected materials and reports from Griffin's involvement with various Baptist organizations. The Civic Engagement series includes records and research for Griffin's involvement with various political and civic organizations, mostly in the Austin area. The Subject Files series includes Griffin's research files relating to all aspects of his career. Finally, the Audio-Visual Materials series includes video tapes, reels and cassette tapes of sermons and speeches by Griffin and other prominent Baptist pastors.
Arrangement
Prior to the latest round of processing, the first donation of the collection was inventoried, processed, and arranged in folders and series according to the current processing standards. At that time, there did not appear to be any original organizational arrangement so the collection was arranged into four series. After this first round of processing was complete, a larger, second donation was given. Since the second donation appeared to be in original order while the first donation had artificial order imposed on it, new series were created to accommodate the incorporation of the first donation into the second. As a result, during current processing, materials from the first donation remained in their folders, retaining dates and titles from the first round of processing. Most of the materials from the second donation were received in folders with dates and titles reflecting their content, so they were placed in new folders with most of the titles and dates retained.
Access Restrictions
All requests for copying of materials must be submitted to The Texas Collection in writing. Please use the Request Form for Copying Materials sheet. Unpublished materials authored or otherwise produced by the creator (s) of this collection are in the public domain. There are no restrictions on use. Copyright status for other collection materials is unknown. Transmission or reproduction of materials protected by U.S. Copyright Law (Title 17, U.S.C.) beyond that allowed by fair use requires the written permission of the copyright owners. Works not in the public domain cannot be commercially exploited without permission of the copyright owners. Responsibility for any use rests exclusively with the user.
Acquisition Information
Accession No. 3837. Acquired 2011-06-27
Related Resources
Items in related collections
[Waco] New Hope Baptist Church records, Inclusive: 1875-1988, Bulk: 1922-1985
Related references
Castillo, Juan. “Longtime East Austin Pastor, Community Builder, Retiring”. The Statesman. 2011 July 8. Accessed 2016 March 23.
Griffin, Marvin C. Texas African-Baptists: The Story of the Missionary Baptist General Convention of Texas. Publisher’s Marketing House, 1994.
HistoryMakers. “Reverent Dr. Marvin Griffin.” ReligionMakers. 2010 May 14. Accessed 2013 February 15.
Who’s Who in the South and Southwest: The Seventh Edition. Chicago: Marquis Publications, 1961.
Electronic Resources
Collection Files
Index Terms
Subjects (Persons)
Griffin, Marvin C.
Subjects (Organizations)
Ebenezer Baptist Church (Austin, Tex.).; New Hope Baptist Church (Waco, Tex.).
Places
Texas -- Race relations.
Subjects
African American Baptists -- Texas -- Waco.; African American churches -- Texas -- Waco.; African Americans -- Civil rights -- Texas.; Baptists -- Sermons.; School Integration -- Texas
Genres
Essays.; Handbooks and manuals.; Interviews (Sound recordings); Scrapbooks.; Slides (Photography); Speeches.; Video recordings.
- Ministry, 1941-2011, undated; 1
  Administrative Information
  Physical Description
  General condition: Excellent.
  Biography/Profile
  The Ministry series contains the research and records of Marvin C. Griffin's pastoral career. The Personal subseries includes mostly research for sermons. The National Baptist subseries includes records of his involvement with various national Baptist conferences and committees. The series is in excellent condition.
  Most of the sermons in Series I, Subseries II are in binders sorted by book of the Bible and include an inventory in the front cover. For example, each binder of sermons on Genesis has an inventory listing of each sermon in that binder, including the sermon title and the date it was given.
  - Personal, 1956-2011, undated; 1
    - “Directions for Teachers”: Marvin C. Griffin: National Baptist Sunday School and Training Union Congress, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - “In Pursuit of Maturity”: Marvin C. Griffin: National Baptist Sunday School and Training Union Congress, 1989 June 13 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - “Keep Telling the Story”: Marvin C. Griffin: National Baptist Sunday School and Training Union Congress, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - “Teaching Christ through the Black Experience”: Marvin C. Griffin: National Baptist Sunday School and Training Union Congress, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - “Teaching Techniques of the Master Teacher”: Marvin C. Griffin: National Baptist Sunday School and Training Union Congress, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - “Training Christian Disicples”: Marvin C. Griffin: National Baptist Sunday School and Training Union Congress, 1977 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - “The Empire Baptist Missionary Convention”, 1966 October 17-21 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - “The Most Beautiful Story Jesus Told”: Marvin C. Griffin: National Baptist Sunday School and Training Union Congress, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Directory: Ebenezer Baptist Church, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Directory: Ebenezer Baptist Church, undated (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Directory: New Hope Baptist Church, circa 1969 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - “A Theological Rationale for the Ebenezer Baptist Church Worship Experience”: Marvin C. Griffin: Doctor of Ministry, 1987 June (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - “Covenant and Liberation in Salvation History”: Marvin C. Griffin: Doctor of Ministry, 1990 April (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - “Commitment to Serve God, Witness of the Black Church” and “Pastors and Deacons”: Marvin C. Griffin, undated (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - “Jeremiah and the New Covenant: Promise of Freedom”, undated (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Manual: Ebenezer Baptist Church: Sunday School, undated (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Historian Papers of National Baptist Convention of America, 1956-2010 (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - Church Program: New Hope Baptist Church (1 of 2), circa 1960s (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Church Program: New Hope Baptist Church (2 of 2), circa 1960s (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Radio Broadcasts (1 of 6), 1964-1966 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Radio Broadcasts (2 of 6), 1964-1966 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Radio Broadcasts (3 of 6), 1964-1966 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Radio Broadcasts (4 of 6), 1964-1966 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Radio Broadcasts (5 of 6), 1964-1966 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Radio Broadcasts (6 of 6), 1964-1966 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Radio Broadcasts (1 of 11), 1967-1968 (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Radio Broadcasts (2 of 11), 1967-1968 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Radio Broadcasts (3 of 11), 1967-1968 (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - Radio Broadcasts (4 of 11), 1967-1968 (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - Radio Broadcasts (5 of 11), 1967-1968 (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Radio Broadcasts (6 of 11), 1967-1968 (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Radio Broadcasts (7 of 11), 1967-1968 (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - Radio Broadcasts (8 of 11), 1967-1968 (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - Radio Broadcasts (9 of 11), 1967-1968 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Radio Broadcasts (10 of 11), 1967-1968 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Radio Broadcasts (11 of 11), 1967-1968 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Sermon Index (1 of 2), undated (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Sermon Index (2 of 2), undated (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - Prayers, General (1 of 4), 1970-1999 (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - Prayers, General (2 of 4), 1970-1999 (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - Prayers, General (3 of 4), 1970-1999 (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - Prayers, General (4 of 4), 1970-1999 (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - Prayers: Marvin C. Griffin, undated (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - Sermon: “God of the Gaps”, 2010 March 21 (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - Sermon: “Good Friday”, undated (Box 3, Folder 12)
    - Sermon: “Good Housekeeping”, 2010 January 17 (Box 3, Folder 13)
    - Sermon: “When the Body Praises God”, undated (Box 3, Folder 14)
    - Sermon: “Workers in the Vineyard”, 2010 December 26 (Box 3, Folder 15)
    - Sermon Notes: Exodus, Acts, Jeremiah, undated (Box 3, Folder 16)
    - Notes on Genesis, undated (Box 3, Folder 17)
    - Sermons on Genesis (1 of 5), 1970-2000 (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Sermons on Genesis (2 of 5), 1970-2000 (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - Sermons on Genesis (3 of 5), 1970-2000 (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Sermons on Genesis (4 of 5), 1970-2000 (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - Sermons on Genesis (5 of 5), 1970-2000 (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - Sermons on Exodus (1 of 5), 1980-2000 (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - Sermons on Exodus (2 of 5), 1980-2000 (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - Sermons on Exodus (3 of 5), 1980-2000 (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - Sermons on Exodus (4 of 5), 1980-2000 (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - Sermons on Exodus (5 of 5), 1980-2000 (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - Sermons on Leviticus, 1973-1983 (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - Sermons on Numbers, 1982-1996 (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - Sermons on Deuteronomy (1 of 2), 1983-2004 (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - Sermons on Deuteronomy (2 of 2), 1983-2004 (Box 6, Folder 8)
    - Sermons on Joshua (1 of 2), 1973-1997 (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - Sermons on Joshua (2 of 2), 1973-1997 (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - Sermons on Judges and Ruth (1 of 2), 1984-2004 (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - Sermons on Judges and Ruth (2 of 2), 1984-2004 (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - Sermons on I Samuel (1 of 3), 1982-2007 (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - Sermons on I Samuel (2 of 3), 1982-2007 (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - Sermons on I Samuel (3 of 3), 1982-2007 (Box 7, Folder 7)
    - Sermons on II Samuel (1 of 2), 1982-1997 (Box 7, Folder 8)
    - Sermons on II Samuel (2 of 2), 1982-1997 (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - Sermons on I Kings (1 of 2), 1979-1997 (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - Sermons on I Kings (2 of 2), 1979-1997 (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - Sermons on II Kings (1 of 2), 1969-2003 (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - Sermons on II Kings (2 of 2), 1969-2003 (Box 8, Folder 5)
    - Sermons on I and II Chronicles, 1982-1991 (Box 8, Folder 6)
    - Sermons on Ezra, 1995 (Box 8, Folder 7)
    - Sermons on Nehemiah, 1988-2001 (Box 8, Folder 8)
    - Sermons on Esther, 1988-2000 (Box 9, Folder 1)
    - Sermons on Job, 2000 (Box 9, Folder 2)
    - Sermons on Psalms (1 of 10), 1980-2003 (Box 9, Folder 3)
    - Sermons on Psalms (2 of 10), 1980-2003 (Box 9, Folder 4)
    - Sermons on Psalms (3 of 10), 1980-2003 (Box 9, Folder 5)
    - Sermons on Psalms (4 of 10), 1980-2003 (Box 9, Folder 6)
    - Sermons on Psalms (5 of 10), 1980-2003 (Box 9, Folder 7)
    - Sermons on Psalms (6 of 10), 1980-2003 (Box 10, Folder 1)
    - Sermons on Psalms (7 of 10), 1980-2003 (Box 10, Folder 2)
    - Sermons on Psalms (8 of 10), 1980-2003 (Box 10, Folder 3)
    - Sermons on Psalms (9 of 10), 1980-2003 (Box 10, Folder 4)
    - Sermons on Psalms (10 of 10), 1980-2003 (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - Sermons on Proverbs, 1977-1998 (Box 11, Folder 2)
    - Sermons on Ecclesiastes and Song of Songs, 1983 (Box 11, Folder 3)
    - Sermons on Isaiah (1 of 2), 1970-2000 (Box 11, Folder 4)
    - Sermons on Isaiah (2 of 2), 1970-2000 (Box 12, Folder 1)
    - Sermons on Jeremiah (1 of 6), 1980-2009 (Box 12, Folder 2)
    - Sermons on Jeremiah (2 of 6), 1980-2009 (Box 12, Folder 3)
    - Sermons on Jeremiah (3 of 6), 1980-2009 (Box 12, Folder 4)
    - Sermons on Jeremiah (4 of 6), 1980-2009 (Box 12, Folder 5)
    - Sermons on Jeremiah (5 of 6), 1980-2009 (Box 13, Folder 1)
    - Sermons on Jeremiah (6 of 6), 1980-2009 (Box 13, Folder 2)
    - Sermons on Ezekiel, 1977 (Box 13, Folder 3)
    - Sermons on Daniel (1 of 2), 1976-2005 (Box 13, Folder 4)
    - Sermons on Daniel (2 of 2), 1976-2005 (Box 13, Folder 5)
    - Sermons on Hosea, 1984-1994 (Box 13, Folder 6)
    - Sermons on Joel, undated (Box 13, Folder 7)
    - Sermons on Amos and Obadiah, 1979 (Box 13, Folder 8)
    - Sermons on Jonah (1 of 2), 1988-2000 (Box 13, Folder 9)
    - Sermons on Jonah (2 of 2), 1988-2000 (Box 13, Folder 10)
    - Sermons on Micah, 1981 (Box 14, Folder 1)
    - Sermons on Malachi, 1978-1982 (Box 14, Folder 2)
    - Sermons on Matthew (1 of 10), 1973-2007 (Box 14, Folder 3)
    - Sermons on Matthew (2 of 10), 1973-2007 (Box 14, Folder 4)
    - Sermons on Matthew (3 of 10), 1973-2007 (Box 14, Folder 5)
    - Sermons on Matthew (4 of 10), 1973-2007 (Box 14, Folder 6)
    - Sermons on Matthew (5 of 10), 1973-2007 (Box 14, Folder 7)
    - Sermons on Matthew (6 of 10), 1973-2007 (Box 14, Folder 8)
    - Sermons on Matthew (7 of 10), 1973-2007 (Box 15, Folder 1)
    - Sermons on Matthew (8 of 10), 1973-2007 (Box 15, Folder 2)
    - Sermons on Matthew (9 of 10), 1973-2007 (Box 15, Folder 3)
    - Sermons on Matthew (10 of 10), 1973-2007 (Box 16, Folder 1)
    - Sermons on Matthew and Mark, 1979-1994 (Box 16, Folder 2)
    - Sermons on Mark (1 of 4), 1967-2006 (Box 16, Folder 3)
    - Sermons on Mark (2 of 4), 1967-2006 (Box 16, Folder 4)
    - Sermons on Mark (3 of 4), 1967-2006 (Box 17, Folder 1)
    - Sermons on Mark (4 of 4), 1967-2006 (Box 17, Folder 2)
    - Sermons on Luke (1 of 12), 1973-2005 (Box 17, Folder 3)
    - Sermons on Luke (2 of 12), 1973-2005 (Box 17, Folder 4)
    - Sermons on Luke (3 of 12), 1973-2005 (Box 18, Folder 1)
    - Sermons on Luke (4 of 12), 1973-2005 (Box 18, Folder 2)
    - Sermons on Luke (5 of 12), 1973-2005 (Box 18, Folder 3)
    - Sermons on Luke (6 of 12), 1973-2005 (Box 18, Folder 4)
    - Sermons on Luke (7 of 12), 1973-2005 (Box 18, Folder 5)
    - Sermons on Luke (8 of 12), 1973-2005 (Box 19, Folder 1)
    - Sermons on Luke (9 of 12), 1973-2005 (Box 19, Folder 2)
    - Sermons on Luke (10 of 12), 1973-2005 (Box 19, Folder 3)
    - Sermons on Luke (11 of 12), 1973-2005 (Box 19, Folder 4)
    - Sermons on Luke (12 of 12), 1973-2005 (Box 19, Folder 5)
    - Sermons on John (1 of 7), 1972-2008 (Box 20, Folder 1)
    - Sermons on John (2 of 7), 1972-2008 (Box 20, Folder 2)
    - Sermons on John (3 of 7), 1972-2008 (Box 20, Folder 3)
    - Sermons on John (4 of 7), 1972-2008 (Box 20, Folder 4)
    - Sermons on John (5 of 7), 1972-2008 (Box 20, Folder 5)
    - Sermons on John (6 of 7), 1972-2008 (Box 21, Folder 1)
    - Sermons on John (7 of 7), 1972-2008 (Box 21, Folder 2)
    - Sermons on Acts (1 of 5), 1971-2008 (Box 21, Folder 3)
    - Sermons on Acts (2 of 5), 1971-2008 (Box 22, Folder 1)
    - Sermons on Acts (3 of 5), 1971-2008 (Box 22, Folder 2)
    - Sermons on Acts (4 of 5), 1971-2008 (Box 22, Folder 3)
    - Sermons on Acts (5 of 5), 1971-2008 (Box 22, Folder 4)
    - Sermons on Romans (1 of 2), 1978-2002 (Box 23, Folder 1)
    - Sermons on Romans (2 of 2), 1978-2002 (Box 23, Folder 2)
    - Outline of I Corinthians, undated (Box 23, Folder 3)
    - Sermons on I Corinthians (1 of 4), 1969-2010 (Box 23, Folder 4)
    - Sermons on I Corinthians (2 of 4), 1969-2010 (Box 23, Folder 5)
    - Sermons on I Corinthians (3 of 4), 1969-2010 (Box 23, Folder 6)
    - Sermons on I Corinthians (4 of 4), 1969-2010 (Box 24, Folder 1)
    - Sermons on II Corinthians, 2010 (Box 24, Folder 2)
    - Sermons on I Corinthians, II Corinthians, Galatians and Ephesians, 1982-2005 (Box 24, Folder 3)
    - Sermons on Galatians, 1971-1984 (Box 24, Folder 4)
    - Sermons on Ephesians, 1978 (Box 24, Folder 5)
    - Sermons on Philippians, 1971-1981 (Box 24, Folder 6)
    - Sermons on Colossians, undated (Box 24, Folder 7)
    - Sermons on Philippians, Colossians, I Thessalonians and II Thessalonians, 1981-1999 (Box 25, Folder 1)
    - Sermons on II Thessalonians, 1967 (Box 25, Folder 2)
    - Sermons on I Timothy, 1981 (Box 25, Folder 3)
    - Sermons on II Timothy, 1981-1984 (Box 25, Folder 4)
    - Sermons on I Timothy and II Timothy, 1989-1999 (Box 25, Folder 5)
    - Sermons on I Timothy, II Timothy and Titus, 1999 (Box 25, Folder 6)
    - Sermons on Titus, undated (Box 25, Folder 7)
    - Sermons on Philemon, undated (Box 25, Folder 8)
    - Sermons on Hebrews (1 of 2), 1971-1999 (Box 25, Folder 9)
    - Sermons on Hebrews (2 of 2), 1971-1999 (Box 26, Folder 1)
    - Sermons on James, 1969-1983 (Box 26, Folder 2)
    - Sermons on I Peter, 1982 (Box 26, Folder 3)
    - Sermons on II Peter, undated (Box 26, Folder 4)
    - Sermons on I John, undated (Box 26, Folder 5)
    - Sermons on Revelations (1 of 4), 1985-1998 (Box 26, Folder 6)
    - Sermons on Revelations (2 of 4), 1985-1998 (Box 26, Folder 7)
    - Sermons on Revelations (3 of 4), 1985-1998 (Box 26, Folder 8)
    - Sermons on Revelations (4 of 4), 1985-1998 (Box 26, Folder 9)
    - Sermons on Judges, I Chronicles, Ezekiel and Zephaniah, 1990-2005 (Box 27, Folder 1)
    - Sermons, General (1 of 27), 1982-2010 (Box 27, Folder 2)
    - Sermons, General (2 of 27), 1982-2010 (Box 27, Folder 3)
    - Sermons, General (3 of 27), 1982-2010 (Box 27, Folder 4)
    - Sermons, General (4 of 27), 1982-2010 (Box 27, Folder 5)
    - Sermons, General (5 of 27), 1982-2010 (Box 27, Folder 6)
    - Sermons, General (6 of 27), 1982-2010 (Box 28, Folder 1)
    - Sermons, General (7 of 27), 1982-2010 (Box 28, Folder 2)
    - Sermons, General (8 of 27), 1982-2010 (Box 28, Folder 3)
    - Sermons, General (9 of 27), 1982-2010 (Box 28, Folder 4)
    - Sermons, General (10 of 27), 1982-2010 (Box 28, Folder 5)
    - Sermons, General (11 of 27), 1982-2010 (Box 28, Folder 6)
    - Sermons, General (12 of 27), 1982-2010 (Box 29, Folder 1)
    - Sermons, General (13 of 27), 1982-2010 (Box 29, Folder 2)
    - Sermons, General (14 of 27), 1982-2010 (Box 29, Folder 3)
    - Sermons, General (15 of 27), 1982-2010 (Box 29, Folder 4)
    - Sermons, General (16 of 27), 1982-2010 (Box 29, Folder 5)
    - Sermons, General (17 of 27), 1982-2010 (Box 29, Folder 6)
    - Sermons, General (18 of 27), 1982-2010 (Box 29, Folder 7)
    - Sermons, General (19 of 27), 1982-2010 (Box 30, Folder 1)
    - Sermons, General (20 of 27), 1982-2010 (Box 30, Folder 2)
    - Sermons, General (21 of 27), 1982-2010 (Box 30, Folder 3)
    - Sermons, General (22 of 27), 1982-2010 (Box 30, Folder 4)
    - Sermons, General (23 of 27), 1982-2010 (Box 30, Folder 5)
    - Sermons, General (24 of 27), 1982-2010 (Box 31, Folder 1)
    - Sermons, General (25 of 27), 1982-2010 (Box 31, Folder 2)
    - Sermons, General (26 of 27), 1982-2010 (Box 31, Folder 3)
    - Sermons, General (27 of 27), 1982-2010 (Box 31, Folder 4)
    - Funerals (1 of 13), 1958-2011 (Box 31, Folder 5)
    - Funerals (2 of 13), 1958-2011 (Box 32, Folder 1)
    - Funerals (3 of 13), 1958-2011 (Box 32, Folder 2)
    - Funerals (4 of 13), 1958-2011 (Box 32, Folder 3)
    - Funerals (5 of 13), 1958-2011 (Box 33, Folder 1)
    - Funerals (6 of 13), 1958-2011 (Box 33, Folder 2)
    - Funerals (7 of 13), 1958-2011 (Box 33, Folder 3)
    - Funerals (8 of 13), 1958-2011 (Box 33, Folder 4)
    - Funerals (9 of 13), 1958-2011 (Box 33, Folder 5)
    - Funerals (10 of 13), 1958-2011 (Box 33, Folder 6)
    - Funerals (11 of 13), 1958-2011 (Box 33, Folder 7)
    - Funerals (12 of 13), 1958-2011 (Box 34, Folder 1)
    - Funerals (13 of 13), 1958-2011 (Box 34, Folder 2)
    - Speeches (1 of 11), 1961-2007 (Box 34, Folder 3)
    - Speeches (2 of 11), 1961-2007 (Box 34, Folder 4)
    - Speeches (3 of 11), 1961-2007 (Box 34, Folder 5)
    - Speeches (4 of 11), 1961-2007 (Box 34, Folder 6)
    - Speeches (5 of 11), 1961-2007 (Box 35, Folder 1)
    - Speeches (6 of 11), 1961-2007 (Box 35, Folder 2)
    - Speeches (7 of 11), 1961-2007 (Box 35, Folder 3)
    - Speeches (8 of 11), 1961-2007 (Box 36, Folder 1)
    - Speeches (9 of 11), 1961-2007 (Box 36, Folder 2)
    - Speeches (10 of 11), 1961-2007 (Box 36, Folder 3)
    - Speeches (11 of 11), 1961-2007 (Box 36, Folder 4)
    - 42nd Pastoral Anniversary and Retirement Celebration, 2011 July 10 (Box 36, Folder 5)
    - Transcription: Oral History Memoir: Marvin C. Griffin, 1975 August 7 (Box 36, Folder 6)
    - Personal Planner, 1990 (Box 36, Folder 7)
    - Personal Planner, 1991 (Box 37, Folder 1)
    - Personal Planner, 1992 (Box 37, Folder 2)